Guide to the Washington State Nurses Association Records
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
- WASHINGTON STATE NURSES ASSOCIATION, 1908-1980; RECORD GROUP I
  - ECONOMIC SECURITY PROGRAM RECORDS, SERIES VIII
    - SUBJECT FILES, 1909-1980; SERIES IX (Box-folder 7/44-8/24, 24/1-25/37, 33/33-34/38, 47/27-48/22, 57/24-58/35, 67/26-68/31, 72/33-72/36)
      - Washington State. Legislative Council Subcommittee on State Institutions and Youth Development, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 25/36)
      - Washington State. Office of Community Development, 1974 (Box-folder 68/29)
      - Washington State Productivity Council, 1975 (Box-folder 68/30)
      - Washington State Public Health Association, 1967-1973 (Box-folder 58/31)
      - Washington State Society of Association Executives, 1970-1973 (Box-folder 58/32)
      - Washington State. Subcommittee of the State Legislative Joint Committee on Education, 1969 (Box-folder 25/37)
      - Washington State University internship program, 1974 (Box-folder 68/31)
      - Washington State Tuberculosis Association, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 58/33)
      - Washington State Women's Council, 1973 (Box-folder 58/34)
      - Washington State Women's Political Caucus, 1973 (Box-folder 58/35)
  - RESEARCH STUDY RECORDS, 1950-1958; SERIES X (Box-folder 8/25-9/30)
    - Job satisfaction study, 1951-1958 (Box-folder 8/25)
    - Poliomyelitis nursing care study (part 1 of 2), 1951-1954 (Box-folder 8/26)
    - Poliomyelitis nursing care study (part 2 of 2), 1951-1954 (Box-folder 8/27)
    - Washington nursing study (part 1 of 5), 1950-1956 (Box-folder 8/28)
    - Washington nursing study (part 2 of 5), 1950-1956 (Box-folder 8/29)
    - Washington nursing study (part 3 of 5), 1950-1956 (Box-folder 8/30)
    - Washington nursing study (part 4 of 5), 1950-1956 (Box-folder 8/31)
    - Washington nursing study (part 5 of 5), 1950-1956 (Box-folder 9/1)
    - Washington nursing study: photograph, 1950 (Box-folder 9/2)
    - Study of nursing functions: grant (part 1 of 3), 1951-1953 (Box-folder 9/3)
    - Study of nursing functions: grant (part 2 of 3), 1951-1953 (Box-folder 9/4)
    - Study of nursing functions: grant (part 3 of 3), 1951-1953 (Box-folder 9/5)
    - Study of nursing functions: Committee on Nursing Services, 1950-1951 (Box-folder 9/6)
    - Study of nursing functions: pilot study, 1951-1953 (Box-folder 9/7)
    - Study of nursing functions: pilot study original data (part 1 of 2), 1951 (Box-folder 9/8)
    - Study of nursing functions: pilot study original data (part 2 of 2), 1951 (Box-folder 9/9)
    - Study of nursing functions: pilot study report, 1951 (Box-folder 9/10)
    - Study of nursing functions: general (part 1 of 3), 1950-1957 (Box-folder 9/11)
    - Study of nursing functions: general (part 2 of 3), 1950-1957 (Box-folder 9/12)
    - Study of nursing functions: general (part 3 of 3), 1950-1957 (Box-folder 9/13)
    - Study of nursing functions: American Nurses' Association correspondence, 1950-1953 (Box-folder 9/14)
    - Study of nursing functions: hospital A, 1952 (Box-folder 9/15)
    - Study of nursing functions: hospital B, 1952 (Box-folder 9/16)
    - Study of nursing functions: hospital C, 1952 (Box-folder 9/17)
    - Study of nursing functions: hospital A worksheets, 1952 (Box-folder 9/18)
    - Study of nursing functions: hospital B worksheets, 1952 (Box-folder 9/19)
    - Study of nursing functions: hospital C data, 1952 (Box-folder 9/20)
    - Study of nursing functions: hospital C worksheets, 1952 (Box-folder 9/21)
    - Study of nursing functions: composite worksheets, 1952 (Box-folder 9/22)
    - Study of nursing functions: final report original, 1953 (Box-folder 9/23)
    - Study of nursing functions: final report, 1953 (Box-folder 9/24)
    - Study of nursing functions: report purchases and loans, 1953-1957 (Box-folder 9/25)
    - Head nurse power and how to use it (part 1 of 2), 1951 (Box-folder 9/26)
    - Head nurse power and how to use it (part 2 of 2), 1951 (Box-folder 9/27)
    - Turnover study in the nursing services unit in Tacoma General Hospital, 1955 (Box-folder 9/28)
    - Human relations factors in administering nursing service in a hospital, 1955 (Box-folder 9/29)
    - A study of job satisfaction among aides in a private psychiatric hospital, 1956 (Box-folder 9/30)
  - REPORTS, 1950-1969; SERIES XI (Box-folder 9/31-10/15)
    - Annual report, 1949-1950 (Box-folder 9/31)
    - Annual report, 1951 (Box-folder 9/32)
    - Annual report, 1952 (Box-folder 10/1)
    - Annual report, 1953 (Box-folder 10/2)
    - Annual report, 1954 (Box-folder 10/3)
    - Annual report, 1955 (Box-folder 10/4)
    - Annual report, 1956 (Box-folder 10/5)
    - Annual report, 1957 (Box-folder 10/6)
    - Annual report, 1958 (Box-folder 10/7)
    - Annual report, 1959 (Box-folder 10/8)
    - Annual report, 1960 (Box-folder 10/9)
    - Annual report, 1961 (Box-folder 10/10)
    - Annual report, 1962 (Box-folder 10/11)
    - Supplementary annual report 1962-1963 (Box-folder 10/12)
    - Washington State League of Nursing Education annual report, 1952 (Box-folder 10/13)
    - Report of Washington Nursing Study, 1950 (Box-folder 10/14)
    - Report on organization study, Harry J. Prior & Associates, 1969 (Box-folder 10/15)
  - SOUND RECORDINGS, 1955-1957; SERIES XII
    - Reminiscences of Miss Cassidy, Elizabeth Sterling Souile, Miss Anna R. Moore, Edna Mason, 1955-1957 (Box-folder 73/1)
    - Meetings of Commitee on Early Nursing Source Material, 1957 (Box-folder 73/2)
    - Washington State Nurses Association Convention, 1955 (Box-folder 73/3)
    - Washington State Nurses Association Convention, 1957 (Box-folder 73/4)
  - PUBLICATION RECORDS / JOURNAL / EPHEMERA, SERIES XIII
    - WASHINGTON STATE NURSES ASSOCIATION PUBLICATIONS, 1925-1974; SUBSERIES I (Box-folder 10/16-11/4, 25/36-26/2, 34/39-34/44, 48/23-48/24, 59/1-59/9, 68/32)
      - Washington State Graduate Nurses Association. The Bulletin, 1938 (Box-folder 10/16)
      - Washington State Journal of Nursing, 1943-1946 (Box-folder 10/17)
      - Washington State Journal of Nursing, 1944-1949 (Box-folder 10/18)
      - Washington State Journal of Nursing, 1950-1951 (Box-folder 10/19)
      - Washington State Journal of Nursing, 1952 (Box-folder 10/20)
      - Washington State Journal of Nursing, 1953 (Box-folder 10/21)
      - Washington State Journal of Nursing, 1954 (Box-folder 10/22)
      - Washington State Journal of Nursing, 1955 (Box-folder 10/23)
      - Washington State Journal of Nursing, 1956 (Box-folder 10/24)
      - Washington State Journal of Nursing, 1957 (Box-folder 10/25)
      - Washington State Journal of Nursing, 1958 (Box-folder 10/26)
      - Washington State Journal of Nursing, 1959 (Box-folder 10/27)
      - Washington State Journal of Nursing, 1960 (Box-folder 10/28)
      - Washington State Journal of Nursing, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 10/29)
      - Washington State Journal of Nursing, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 10/30)
      - Washington State Journal of Nursing, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 10/31)
      - Washington State Journal of Nursing, 1967 (Box-folder 10/32)
      - Washington State Journal of Nursing, 1968 (Box-folder 10/33)
      - Journal feature articles, 1943 (Box-folder 11/1)
      - Copy for March Journal, 1950 (Box-folder 34/39)
      - Photographs for Journal use, 1950s (Box-folder 34/40)
      - Journal correspondence, 1951 (Box-folder 11/2)
      - Journal feature articles, 1951 (Box-folder 11/3)
      - Journal reference material, 1951 (Box-folder 11/4)
      - WSNA Legislative Bulletin, 1960-1965 (Box-folder 48/24)
      - WSNA Legislative Bulletin, 1964 (Box-folder 25/36)
      - WSNA Legislative Bulletin, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 25/37)
      - WSNA Legislative Bulletin, 1969 (Box-folder 25/38)
      - WSNA Legislative Bulletin, 1970 (Box-folder 25/39)
      - WSNA Legislative Bulletin, 1962-1968 (Box-folder 59/4)
      - WSNA Legislative Bulletin, 1969 (Box-folder 59/5)
      - WSNA Legislative Bulletin, 1970 (Box-folder 59/6)
      - WSNA Legislative Bulletin, 1971 (Box-folder 59/7)
      - WSNA Legislative Bulletin, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 59/8)
      - WSNA Local Unit Bulletin, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 68/32)
      - Section newsletter, 1965 (Box-folder 34/41)
      - Joint section newsletter, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 48/23)
      - Washington State Nurses Association Section News, 1966 (Box-folder 34/42)
      - Washington State Nurses Association publications on nursing history, 1925-1939 (Box-folder 34/43)
      - Fifty years with Washington State Nurses Association 1903-1953, 1954 (Box-folder 34/44)
      - Recommendations for action: preparation and utilization of nurses in the State of Washington, 1971 (Box-folder 26/1)
      - A statement on the implications of the American Nurses' Association position paper for the State of Washington, 1968 (Box-folder 26/2)
      - Careers Committee handbook, 1970 (Box-folder 59/1)
      - CONP Digest, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 59/2)
      - Continuing Education for Registered Nurses, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 59/3)
      - WSNA Mini Journal, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 59/9)
    - PUBLICATIONS OF OTHERS, 1929-1975; SUBSERIES II (Box-folder 11/5-11/17, 26/3-26/7, 35/1-35/19, 48/25-48/30, 59/10-59/18, 68/33)
      - Article reprints, 1947-1963 (Box-folder 11/5)
      - Publications, 1930-1952 (Box-folder 11/6)
      - International Labour Office. Employment and conditions of work for nurses, 1960 (Box-folder 11/7)
      - American Nurses' Association Bulletin, 1930-1931 (Box-folder 35/1)
      - American Nurses' Association Bulletin, 1932-1933 (Box-folder 35/2)
      - American Nurses' Association Bulletin, 1934 (Box-folder 35/3)
      - American Nurses' Association Bulletin, 1938 (Box-folder 35/4)
      - American Nurses' Association. Manual for the guidance of boards of directors and headquarters staffs of state nursing associations, 1955 (Box-folder 11/8)
      - American Nurses' Association. Nurses invest in patient care, 1956 (Box-folder 11/9)
      - American Nurses' Association. Past, present and future of FS and Q, 1957 (Box-folder 11/10)
      - American Nurses' Association. Special committee on employment conditions of registered nurses. Report, 1954 (Box-folder 11/11)
      - Toward quality in nursing: needs and goals, 1963 (Box-folder 11/12)
      - American Nurses' Association. Bylaws, 1966 (Box-folder 11/13)
      - American Nurses' Association. Selected provisions from state nurses associations employment standards, 1966-1968 (Box-folder 11/14)
      - International Council of Nurses. Report of the economic consultant, 1957 (Box-folder 11/15)
      - International Council of Nurses. Report of the Economic Welfare Committee, 1953 (Box-folder 11/16)
      - ICN Calling (newsletter), 1968-1970 (Box-folder 35/5)
      - Newsletters, 1969 (Box-folder 11/17)
      - Proposed plan for functions and structure of American Nurses' Association 1965 supplement (Box-folder 26/3)
      - A report to members 1966-1968 (Box-folder 26/4)
      - Capital Commentary, 1966-1969 (Box-folder 26/5)
      - Report of a questionnaire study on registered nurses in the State of Washington, 1961 (Box-folder 26/6)
      - Summary of annual reports from state nurses associations, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 26/7)
      - Nursing history: American Nurses' Association publications, 1929-1950 (Box-folder 35/6)
      - Nursing history: other states, 1952-1957 (Box-folder 35/7)
      - American Nurses' Association. Employment conditions of nurses employed by physicians and/or dentists, 1962-1964 (Box-folder 35/8)
      - American Nurses' Association. For public health nurses transportation, 1961 (Box-folder 35/9)
      - American Nurses' Association. Give a little -- get a lot, 1955 (Box-folder 35/10)
      - American Nurses' Association. Preparing an economic brief for public health nurses, 1959 (Box-folder 35/11)
      - American Nurses' Association. Professional standards -- whose responsibility?, 1963 (Box-folder 35/12)
      - American Nurses' Association. Selected provisions from state nurses associations employment standards, 1963-1965 (Box-folder 35/13)
      - American Nurses' Association. Summary of annual reports from state nurses associations, 1966 (Box-folder 35/14)
      - American Nurses' Association. Survey of salaries and employment conditions in nonfederal psychiatric hospitals, 1965 (Box-folder 35/15)
      - American Nurses' Association. Survey of state nursing association activities, 1967 (Box-folder 35/16)
      - American Nurses' Association. Target -- better section meetings, 1959 (Box-folder 35/17)
      - American Nurses' Association. Teachers and administrators salary survey, 1964-1966 (Box-folder 35/18)
      - American Nurses' Association publications, 1952-1965 (Box-folder 35/19)
      - American Nurses' Association bylaws, 1956-1966 (Box-folder 48/25)
      - American Nurses' Association publications, 1961-1969 (Box-folder 48/26)
      - Capital Commentary, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 48/27)
      - Economic Security News, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 48/28)
      - Guide on recommended personnel policies for nurses, 1964 (Box-folder 48/29)
      - Manual for sections, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 48/30)
      - ANA in Action, 1967-1971 (Box-folder 59/10)
      - ANA Registry Manual, 1966 (Box-folder 59/11)
      - The American Nurse newspaper, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 59/12)
      - American Nurses' Foundation newsletters, 1970-1973 (Box-folder 59/13)
      - Capital Commentary, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 59/14)
      - Licensed Practical Nurse Association Washington State publications, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 59/15)
      - Professional Registry Guidelines, 1961-1970 (Box-folder 59/16)
      - School Nurses of Washington State newsletter, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 59/17)
      - State of Washington Association Nursing Students newsletters, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 59/18)
      - E & GW Hotline, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 68/33)
    - EPHEMERA, 1922-1970; SUBSERIES III (Box-folder 12/1-12/4, 26/10-26/11, 35/20-35/28, 48/31-48/35)
      - Washington State Nurses Association convention banquet programs, 1927-1962 (Box-folder 35/20)
      - American Nurses' Association reprints and pamphlets, 1930-1968 (Box-folder 35/21)
      - Publications of others, 1940-1949 (Box-folder 35/22)
      - The Link, c. 1923 (Box-folder 35/23)
      - Firland: a story of Firland Sanatorium, c. 1936 (Box-folder 35/24)
      - Beginnings, progress and achievement in the medical work of King County, Washington, c. 1931 (Box-folder 35/25)
      - National League of Nursing Education calendars, 1922-1923 (Box-folder 35/26)
      - National League of Nursing Education calendars, 1925-1927 (Box-folder 35/27)
      - National League of Nursing Education calendars, 1929-1932 (Box-folder 35/28)
      - American Nurses' Association welcome to Washington nurses, 1932 (Box-folder 12/1)
      - The code for professional nurses, undated, 1950 (Box-folder 12/2)
      - Nursing information scrapbook, 1945 (Box-folder 12/3)
      - Professional Nurse Day scrapbook, 1963 (Box-folder 12/4)
      - Professional Nurse Week careers in nursing materials, 1967 (Box-folder 26/8)
      - Professional Nurse Week banners, 1970 (Box-folder 26/9)
      - Professional Nurse Week tv title slides, 1970 (Box-folder 26/10)
      - Brochures and pamphlets, 1947-1967 (Box-folder 26/11)
      - Geriatrics pamphlets, 1954-1964 (Box-folder 48/31)
      - Nursing careers pamphlets (part 1 of 2), 1960-1968 (Box-folder 48/32)
      - Nursing careers pamphlets (part 2 of 2), 1960-1968 (Box-folder 48/33)
      - Occupational health pamphlets, 1962 (Box-folder 48/34)
      - Office nurse pamphlets, 1958-1966 (Box-folder 48/35)
  - WASHINGTON STATE HEALTH COUNCIL RECORDS, 1956-1962; SERIES XIV (Box-folder 11/18-11/24)
    - Constitution and by-laws, 1956-1962 (Box-folder 11/18)
    - Meeting records and correspondence, 1958-1960 (Box-folder 11/19)
    - Meeting records and correspondence, 1961 (Box-folder 11/20)
    - Meeting records and correspondence, 1962 (Box-folder 11/21)
    - Careers Committee, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 11/22)
    - Ten year summary report of the Washington State Health Council, 1960 (Box-folder 11/23)
    - Washington State Health Council Bulletin, 1954-1962 (Box-folder 11/24)
  - WASHINGTON STATE JOINT COMMISSION FOR THE IMPROVEMENT OF THE CARE OF THE PATIENT (JCICP) RECORDS, 1954-1962; SERIES XV (Box-folder 11/25-11/30)
    - Administrative regulations, 1958-1962 (Box-folder 11/25)
    - Minutes, 1954-1962 (Box-folder 11/26)
    - Membership lists, 1955-1962 (Box-folder 11/27)
    - Correspondence, 1956-1962 (Box-folder 11/28)
    - Reports and ephemera (part 1 of 2), 1957-1958 (Box-folder 11/29)
    - Reports and ephemera (part 2 of 2), 1957-1958 (Box-folder 11/30)
  - POLITICALLY UNITED NURSES FOR CONSUMER HEALTH, 1972-1974; Records Subgroup 1 (Box-folder 68/34-68/38)
    - General correspondence, 1972 (Box-folder 68/34)
    - General correspondence, 1973 (Box-folder 68/35)
    - General correspondence, 1974 (Box-folder 68/36)
    - Board of Trustees minutes and meeting notices, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 68/37)
    - Financial records, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 68/38)
- WASHINGTON STATE ORGANIZATION FOR PUBLIC HEALTH NURSING, 1936-1949; RECORD GROUP II (Box-folder 11/31-11/45, 35/29-35/37)
  - Minutes, 1941-1945 (Box-folder 35/29)
  - Minutes, 1945-1947 (Box-folder 11/31)
  - Records and history, 1940-1941 (Box-folder 35/31)
  - Correspondence, 1939-1940 (Box-folder 35/32)
  - Correspondence, 1941 (Box-folder 35/33)
  - Correspondence, 1942 (Box-folder 35/34)
  - Correspondence, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 35/35)
  - Correspondence, 1943-1949 (Box-folder 11/32)
  - Ledger, 1936-1948 (Box-folder 11/33)
  - Treasurer's reports, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 11/34)
  - Membership lists, 1945-1947 (Box-folder 11/35)
  - Officer and membership lists, 1943-1945 (Box-folder 35/30)
  - Membership applications, 1947 (Box-folder 11/36)
  - Program Committee, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 11/37)
  - Finance Committee, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 11/38)
  - Standards Committee, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 11/39)
  - Publicity Committee, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 11/40)
  - Special committee assignments, 1947 (Box-folder 11/41)
  - Council of Branches, 1946 (Box-folder 11/42)
  - Annual report, 1940 (Box-folder 35/36)
  - Washington State Nurses' Association, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 11/43)
  - National Organization for Public Health Nursing, 1941-1945 (Box-folder 35/37)
  - National Organization for Public Health Nursing, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 11/44)
  - United States Public Health Service, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 11/45)
- STATE OF WASHINGTON ASSOCIATED NURSING STUDENTS, 1957-1970; RECORD GROUP III (Box-folder 11/46-11/53, 35/38-35/41)
  - Bylaws, 1961-1964 (Box-folder 11/46)
  - Bylaws, 1964 (Box-folder 35/38)
  - Minutes (part 1 of 2), 1958-1965 (Box-folder 11/47)
  - Minutes (part 2 of 2), 1958-1965 (Box-folder 11/48)
  - Minutes and correspondence (part 1 of 2), 1965-1967 (Box-folder 35/40)
  - Minutes and correspondence (part 2 of 2), 1965-1967 (Box-folder 35/41)
  - Minutes, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 11/49)
  - Annual reports, 1965-1965 (Box-folder 11/50)
  - Membership lists, 1962-1966 (Box-folder 11/51)
  - Policy handbook, 1965 (Box-folder 35/39)
  - Correspondence, 1963-1965 (Box-folder 11/52)
  - Convention records, 1957-1962 (Box-folder 11/53)